<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King Charles by the grace of God, King of Great Brittain, France and Ireland, defender of the faith; to all and sundry his lieges and subjects, greeting. ...</title>
            <title>Miscellaneous Documents. 1650-07-27</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1660-1685 : Charles II)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B20147</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886271</idno>
  <idno type="VID">188458</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240894860</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C3610I</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 1851.c.11[45]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225775</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886271</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886271e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B20147)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 188458)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C10:3[35])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King Charles by the grace of God, King of Great Brittain, France and Ireland, defender of the faith; to all and sundry his lieges and subjects, greeting. ...</title>
                  <title>Miscellaneous Documents. 1650-07-27</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1660-1685 : Charles II)</author>
                  <author>Charles II, King of England, 1630-1685.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by Evan Tyler,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1650]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title taken from caption title and first lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Dated at end: Given at our castle of Sterling, the 27. of July. And of our reign, the second. 1650.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing CD-ROM, 1996.</note>
                  <note>Arms 223; Steele notation: and Maiesty our.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
                  <note>Copy cropped at foot affecting imprint.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="uniform_title">Solemn League and Covenant 1643 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:188458:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>C R</head>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon surmounted by a crown</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>BY THE KING</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>HARLES By the Grace of God, King of <hi>Great Brittain, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> Defender of the Faith; To all and sundry his Lieges and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, greeting.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>VVhereas the Lord hath been pleased in his gracious goodnesse and tender mercy, to discover unto his Maiesty the great evill of the wayes wherein he hath been formerly led by wicked Counsell, and hath so far blessed the endeavours of this Kirk and Kingdome, as his Maiesty hath now sworne and subscribed the Solemn League and Covenant, and given satisfaction to their desires: And whereas his Maiesty is most willing and desirous to grant the Propositions of both Kingdoms presented to his Royall Father at New-Castle, and Hampton-Court, with such alte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rations and additions as shall be thought necessary for the good of King and Kingdoms, and to give such farther satisfaction to his people of <hi>England,</hi> as shall be desired by his two Houses of the Parliament of <hi>England,</hi> sitting in Freedom. And forasmuch as an Army from he Sectarian party in <hi>England,</hi> under the Command of L. G. <hi>Cromwell,</hi> after all the evill and wickednesse committed in <hi>England,</hi> in murthering his Majesties Royall Father, using force against the two Houses of Parliament, and oppressing their fellow Subiects in <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> hath now also invaded this Kingdom, contrary to the solemn League and Covenant, and the Treaty betwixt the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>domes, wherein his Maiesty is perswaded, that many of the Officers and Souldiers of the said Army have been misled through the craft and subtilty of others, who have contrived and design<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the subversion of all Government, Civill and Ecclesiasticall in all the three Kingdoms, and to subiect all persons to their Tyrannicall usurpation and domination. Therefore his Maiesty from the pious and tender care he hath to reclaime his Subiects from such unlawfull and rebellious courses, doth hereby offer a free Pardon and Indemnity to all Officers and Souldiers of the said <hi>English</hi> Army now within this Kingdom, for any thing done, or acted by them against his Majesty and his Royal Father, during these troubles, who shal immediately upon sight of this his Majesties gracious offer leave that Army, and come over to the Scottish Army, where they shal be courte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ously used and entertained; Provided alwayes that this his Maiesties offer shal not be understood to comprehend any person or persons, who after the said force used against the Houses of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, having sitten in the pretended House of Commons, or in any other Court, pretending power from them, did vote the taking away of his Maiesties Royall fathers life;</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given at our Castle of <hi>Sterling,</hi>
                  <date>the 27. of <hi>July.</hi> And of our Reign, the Second year, 1650.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>